(phone buzzing)
Oh...
(coughing)
Shit.
(sighs)
Are you coming back tonight?
Um...
No...
Thanks.
(piano music)
*
(dog barking in distance)
(door opening)
Are you high?
Not really.
Jesus.
You have to put it up.
My hair.
Leave it.
This is really important, okay?
-I got it.
-I'm being serious.
I got it.
Monique is really
good for me.
She knows people,
and they're all gonna be there.
I got it.
It's also good for Lottie.
Why else do you think
I'd be here?
(jazzy music)
*
(engine turns over)
(gasps)
Oh, happy Juneteenth!
Oh, Vanessa.
You look amazing.
Oh, thank you so much
for having us.
And hello.
I'm Monique.
You must be Mr. Hubby?
This is Earnest.
Yeah. Me.
Mr. Hubby.
Oh, well, come inside,
come inside.
-* I got a rope
all: * Huh!
* Into thy kingdom
-* Ain't that good news
Are they up for auction
after the party, or--
(laughter)
Uh-uh-uh.
So, to the left,
we have the bar.
To the right,
we have the bathroom.
Oh, we have bathrooms
upstairs, downstairs--
many, many bathrooms.
And where is Craig?
Happy Freedom Day!
(chuckles)
Mm, mm, mm.
Welcome.
Craig, Monique's husband.
You're familiar.
Cherokee?
Uh, no.
Just black.
(laughter)
No, Cherokee Town
and Country Club.
You're a member, right?
Uh, no, no, no.
-You sure?
-Yes.
You must be confusing me
with some other black guy.
-* Ain't that good news
-Ah!
You don't think I'm capable
of telling African-Americans
apart?
N--no.
(laughing)
Just messing with you, man.
Welcome.
God, it is so great
to meet both of you.
* I got a savior
So, do you want
to get me a drink?
Anything?
Like a vodka cranberry?
Anything for you.
(jazz music)
-Hey, could I get a, uh--
-Sir.
I'll be right with you
soon as you take your place
in the queue--
the line?
I know what a queue is.
*
Thank you.
How can I help you, sir?
Yeah, I'd like, uh,
a vodka cranberry.
I'm sorry, sir, we aren't
equipped to make that drink.
-A screwdriver, then.
-Sir.
We have a fixed cocktail menu
for the evening.
Please make a selection.
*
"Juneteenth Juice.
Frozen Freedom Margarita.
Emancipation Eggnog."
It's June.
Nigga, do I got to explain
alliteration? Hmm?
I'll have the Plantation
Master Poison.
(rattling)
-So sorry about Earnest.
-Princeton--
He just thinks he's so funny--
Oh, don't be, girl.
I like him.
Ramon!
Mm!
Smile.
This is a celebration.
Not an orphanage.
Hmm?
*
(sighs)
I'm glad you came.
Mm-hmm.
I know we haven't known
each other for a long time,
but I mean it when I say...
you remind me of me.
And we're gonna make sure
you get everything you want.
Still want to be a teacher?
The principal of Pace University
is here.
Easy--want to be a designer,
an event planner,
-a real housewife?
-Girl, quit playing--
Shh!
You can have anything
that you want.
You are a smart, beautiful,
and determined lady
like me.
And your fancy Ivy League
husband is here,
so there's no problem there.
Thanks, Mo.
-Glad you came.
-(chuckles)
*
(traditional choral music)
(whispering)
What the fuck?
Nobody can give you freedom.
Nobody can give you equality,
or justice, or anything.
If you're a man, you take it.
Malcolm X quote
that inspired that painting.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to--
Stop, stop.
You're fine.
You--you want a real drink?
-Sure.
-All right.
*
That's a...interesting
interpretation of that quote.
*
It's the only interpretation.
It accurately depicts the plight
of the contemporary black man.
That is why I painted it.
Wow.
So, Earn.
What kind of business you in?
Music management.
-Yes.
-Yes?
No, it's just--it's nice.
A brother on the business side
of music.
-What do you mean?
-Mm.
Please.
Well, music is
such an integral part
of the African-American culture.
It's expression.
And it's been stripped from you.
Black music artists are products
for white American consumption
and appropriation.
Mm.
Is this Hennessy?
Mm-hmm.
Are you an archaeologist
in African studies?
I'm an optometrist.
I see a picture of you
in Africa over there.
Oh, that.
Yeah, that was--whew.
That was a pilgrimage.
Needed to pay my respects.
Ask for forgiveness--
well, you know, right?
I don't.
I really don't.
What, you--you've never
been to Africa?
No.
You got to go!
Man, it's your motherland.
What are you thinking?
Missing--what are you?
Huh?
What?
Where are your ancestors from?
Congo?
Ivory Coast?
Southeastern Bantu region.
I don't know--this spooky thing
called "slavery" happened,
and my entire ethnic identity
was erased, so...
(chuckling)
Exactly.
(light jazz music)
*
Where have you been?
You sure you want to...
stay here the whole time?
Yes.
Are you sure, though?
Earn.
It doesn't feel like you're in
a Spike Lee-directed
"Eyes Wide Shut" right now?
Hmm?
*
Are these slave ships?
Do you think
that I am happy here,
having to prostitute myself
for an opportunity?
Maybe.
*
Do you think that I'm happy
that I need you here
in order to do that?
Maybe.
*
Can we, for once,
just pretend that we aren't
who we are?
I mean, because we both know
that you're good at pretending.
*
Mm.
I prefer Craig Mack.
(laughing)
If you--if you're gonna ask.
I have to say this.
You remind me of a character
in my new play.
-Really?
-You do.
-Oh. Mm.
-You really do.
So comical.
And handsome!
-Oh!
-Ooh.
Vanessa, you must be
in stitches every day,
married to such a funny man.
Mm.
Well, as I always say,
you have to laugh
to keep from crying.
Yeah, she always says that.
-Yes.
-You should slow down.
We're going up at the Rialto
next month.
My play,
"With Tail Between Legs."
-Mm, good title.
-I wrote and directed it.
It all takes place
at a strip club.
Two gangbangers hold a pastor,
a drug dealer,
and a pregnant teen hostage
in the middle of
Hurricane Katrina.
-That's a real situation.
-Mm! Sad.
I'm glad
that story's being told.
We've already adapted it
into a movie.
-We would love to read that.
-Love.
You know, and we were just
saying this the other day.
(both stammering)
both: The quality...
-Of theater is just gone.
-Of theater is just not there.
-It's just not there.
-Anymore.
It's just not there.
Well, let me
tell you something.
Black Americans have to keep
fighting for good art.
-A-men! Come--mm!
-We have to.
both: Mm-hmm.
-Hmm.
-(laughing)
-We really do.
-Mm-hmm.
(laughs)
Oh.
Yeah, we really do.
Yep.
-Ah.
-Is Vin Diesel black?
*
And all you got to do
is give it up
to Jesus, playboy.
Mm.
I don't think
we really have the time
to be church people.
Yeah, between going to
Lottie's cello recitals
and volunteering for at-risk
Filipino youth--
See, there--
there you go again.
Doubting!
The devil has clouded
your mind with doubt.
Now, I'm not just a reverend
at some church.
No.
You see, I am a reverend
at a mega-church.
-Yeah, you said that--
-Yeah, you kind of say that--
-Like twice already.
-Often.
And I am gonna teach you both
about money management.
And how to treat your woman.
With respect.
Hmm!
Player, she wants a new you.
She wants a saved man,
a man with a bangin' body
and money in the bank.
She's a pretty woman.
Thank you.
(laughing)
-Yes.
-Yeah.
What--what was your name?
And what do you do, Earn?
Nothing.
(laughter)
I mean that.
Van does everything.
She works,
she raises our child,
she's smarter than me,
better than me.
I mean,
that's why I married her.
She honestly doesn't get
the credit she deserves.
I mean, ever.
But that doesn't deter her
from being what she is,
which is a mother,
a provider,
and a partner.
Gun to my head,
I don't think I could even
look at another woman.
(soft jazz music)
*
Vanessa, we're looking
for new members
in our Jack and Jill
Atlanta chapter.
You'd be a great fit.
-We have a sickle cell--
-I'm so sorry, um...
Will you excuse me?
I...
*
She's fine.
(sighs)
(distant party chatter)
(deep breath)
What am I doing?
(crying)
What the fuck am I doing?
*
Hey.
What's wrong?
You're mean.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
I'm getting drunk.
*
Oh, people cannot stop talking
about you two.
Hey, Earn.
Listen, I--
I'm about to do
a poetry reading,
and I tell you, I--
I would love to have you
front and center
and hear your thoughts.
That sounds splendid.
(lighter clicks)
Seems like Earn and Craig
are hitting it off.
(exhales)
Craig, Craig, Craig, Craig.
You don't think I know how crazy
my husband is?
This whole "Black people
as a hobby" shit?
Slam poetry?
"Martin" reruns?
That nigga told
my 95-year-old grandmother
that she was cooking
her collard greens wrong.
(laughter)
Well, girl, you married him.
Yeah, I did.
Can't eat if you don't
open your mouth.
I get this big-ass house,
and he gets
the black wife he always wanted.
(chuckles)
That's marriage.
I like Craig.
But I love my money.
You did good.
You married right, huh?
Only way to stay fed
in this world
is to keep the right company.
Do you ever wish
that you actually
had somebody to confide in?
Hmm?
Uh...
It just seems really obvious
that you don't think
Craig understands you.
Are you sorry
that you can't have
understanding and security?
That reminds me of something.
Something that Craig
actually made me read.
It goes something like,
"It's redundant to be both
black and sorry
in the world."
It's kind of like that.
Hmm?
That's from
"For Colored Girls."
Oh.
(laughter)
Oh, ugh.
Come on.
Let's go back inside.
Make sure our husbands
are behaving.
(beatboxing)
Jim Crow!
Has the name of a man, but...
is a ghost.
I am a man.
But Jim Crow
is haunting me,
like in that movie
"Poltergeist."
And I am stuck
in a television,
like that little girl.
Just get me out of here--
I don't want to be
in an electrical
appliance.
(scatting)
(hollow echoing)
Oh, but my point is moot.
I have seen strange fruit
loaded in this garden
of Eden...
(whirring drowning out voices)
-(slamming)
-Shit.
-Oh, yes. They are here.
-Sorry.
-It's okay.
-Sorry about that, man.
-Feeding and feeding...
-Is that Red Bull and vodka?
Well, yeah, but, uh, look,
don't tell my wife.
I'm not supposed to have
too much caffeine.
-Where did you get that?
-Bar.
-I am a man, but...
-Jim Crow is haunting me.
-Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Hey, you're Paper Boi's
dude, ain't you?
-Can we get a picture?
-Uh...of--of me?
I guess. You here.
He here?
No, he's not--actually,
right now's not a good time.
-(snorts)
-Hey.
Well, can you pass Paper Boi
a message for me?
Yeah, tell him
my sister likes him?
-Okay.
-All right.
-Here's a pair of her underwear.
-Whoa.
-Give it to Paper Boi.
-Why? No.
-Her name Tangela.
-Why are you--no.
Why do you have
your sister's underwear?
-(snorts) Never know, man.
-Never know what?
No. Out. Out.
No, no. Go.
If you want more food,
Ramon will bring you
a to-go plate outside.
-Earn.
-Okay, good-bye.
Hey, man.
What'd you think?
I would love any
honest criticism.
-Uh-uh. No, no.
-Is everything okay?
Yeah, we straight,
we were just
saying "What's up"
to Paper Boi's boy.
-(laughing)
-Paper Boi?
(laughter)
Oh, my...
They must be confusing you.
-That's funny.
-Paper Boi.
-Confused with someone else.
-Someone else.
Paper Boi!
I knew it!
I knew
I knew you from somewhere.
I had such a special feeling
about you, Earn.
Honey--honey,
Earn is Paper Boi's manager.
Oh, sorry.
A very, very talented
young rapper.
Oh, you manage rap?
(clears throat)
Yes.
I manage rap.
There is nothing wrong
with earning money
doing something with rap,
it's fine.
Well, it's not just
about money.
You know it's--you know,
he--he's my cousin.
-He's family.
-Yeah.
Honey, you're missing the point.
It's not about money.
This is bigger than money.
Paper Boi is underground.
I've been following Paper Boi
since the start.
That's how I knew you!
I mean, since the shooting?
Your pictures were everywhere.
Shooting?
Well, you aren't gonna
shoot up this party,
are you, Earn?
Mm...no,
I wasn't planning on it.
(laughing)
I'm kidding.
I get it.
Can't choose your family, huh?
Every decent person has at least
one trifling thug in the family.
(chuckles)
Oh, honey, let's go
say "hello" to--
Eh, no.
I'm sorry.
This is whack.
This is--this is whack.
-Babe, please.
-No, no.
Okay, like, this isn't
real life, okay?
This--this party is dumb.
She's dumb.
This is all dumb.
You know that, Van.
-This is dumb.
-Okay. I'm sorry.
-We're gonna head out, right?
And you know what?
Stop stunting on me
about my culture.
Like, I'm not gonna
go back to Africa
and find my roots,
because you know what?
-I'm sorry.
-I'm fucking broke, dude.
-I'm broke.
-It's my bad.
-No, don't do that.
-Hey.
Don't "my bad" it.
And stop being so likable.
Stop being so likable,
like, I get--don't--
and don't be like
"I understand"--
-Earn, we're heading out now.
-Because you don't understand.
-We're going now.
-Like, I'm--
-Good night.
-For your hospitality.
Okay, well, we--we'd love
to see you soon.
Thank you very much for coming.
-Mm-hmm.
-Good night.
-Happy Juneteenth.
-So weird.
-Great party. Let's go, babe.
So weird.
This is a weird place.
(engine rumbling)
I'll call her in the morning
and apologize.
I'm sorry.
Pull over.
You sick?
You okay?
("Chain Gang" by Sam Cooke)
*
* I hear something saying
* Uh!
* Ah!
-* Ah!
-* Well, don't you know
* That's the sound
of the men *
* Working on the chain
* Gang
* That's the sound of the men
* Working on the chain gang
* All day long,
they're saying *
* Uh!
* Ah!
-* Ah!
-* Well, don't you know
* That's the sound
of the men *
* Working on the chain
* Gang
* That's the sound of the men
* Working on the chain gang
* All day long,
they work so hard *
* Till the sun
* Is going down
* Working on the highways
and byways *
* And wearing,
wearing a frown *
* You hear them moaning
their lives away... *